Guide to the Yale Psychiatric Institute Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale Psychiatric Institute records
1975-1990
RU 454
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
7.75
The records consist of administrative papers, committee minutes, and reports concerning the planning and construction of a new building for the Yale Psychiatric Institute (YPI, formerly the Department of Psychiatry).
Yale University. School of Medicine
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 27-E (YRG 27-E), Records of departments, offices, programs, and projects of the Yale School of Medicine.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of administrative papers, committee minutes, and reports concerning the planning and construction of a new building for the Yale Psychiatric Institute (YPI, formerly the Department of Psychiatry).
Related Materials
The records of Myron Genel, Associate Dean, School of Medicine (RU 1131) contains a series (.5 linear feet) of subject files, affirmative action and development records of the Yale Psychiatric Institute.
Psychiatry; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Buildings; Yale University. Department of Psychiatry; Yale University. School of Medicine
- Records, 1975-1984; Accession 1986-A-047
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2019
  - Night Reports (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Monthly Meetings, 1975
    - Jan (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Feb (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Mar (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Apr (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - May (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Jun (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Jul (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Aug (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Sep (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Oct (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Nov (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Coordinating Committee, 1975 January-December (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Staff Meetings (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - International Working Meeting (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Patient Care Data (Box 1, Folder 16 - 17)
  - Full-Time Equivalents (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Statement of Mission (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - SYND/Bond Model (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Blue Stock (Box 2, Folder 21 - 23)
  - Certificate of Need Application (Box 2, Folder 24 - 26)
  - Barun Baru Associates: Long Range Plan, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 27 - 28)
  - Long-Range Plans (Box 3, Folder 29 - 31)
  - Executive Comfttee (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Commission on Hospitals and Health Care: Text of Public Statutes, etc. (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Ad Hoc Planning Committee
    - Financial Statements (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - 1975 May 27 (Box 3, Folder 35 - 36)
    - 1983 May 4 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - New Haven - Development (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Medical Center - Main Site Options (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Main Site Options (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Site Options, 1975 October 14 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Yale University Site Evaluations (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Albertus Magnus (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Howard/Vernon (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Prospect/Mansfield (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Yale (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Project Progress Reports (Box 4, Folder 47 - 48)
  - Health Systems, Incorporated - Application (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Site Overview (Box 4, Folder 50 - 52)
  - Facility Planning (Box 5, Folder 53 - 54)
  - Sites and Facility Development (Box 5, Folder 55 - 56)
  - Certificate of Need
    - Application (Box 5, Folder 57 - 59)
    - Attachments (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - 1984 May 18 (Box 6, Folder 61 - 63)
  - Architect Selection (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Progress Reports
    - 1982 Dec 1 (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - 1983 Apr 15 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Administrative Planning Team
    - 1983 Jan 21 (Box 6, Folder 67)
    - 1983 Feb 18 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Ad Hoc Planning Committee
    - 1981 Oct 27 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - Final Report, 1983 April 5 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Final Report, 1983 April 7 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Proposal for Consulting Services, 1981 June 25 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Data Base, 1981 September 18 (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - Functional Narratives and Space Program
    - Preliminary (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - 1983 Nov (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - Final (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Architects - Joint Venture (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Cost Cornissfon (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - Board Minutes and Corresponding Information (Box 8, Folder 79 - 80)
  - Governing Body (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Accreditation
    - Survey (Box 8, Folder 82)
    - JCAH, 1982 April (Box 9, Folder 83 - 84)
    - 1980 (Box 9, Folder 85)
    - 1980-1982 (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - Planning/Zoning Committee (Box 10, Folder 90)
  - Preliminary Report: Overall Site Development (Box 10, Folder 91)
  - YPI Governing Board (Box 10, Folder 92)
  - Administrative Sub-Committee (Box 10, Folder 93)
  - Cost Commission (Box 10, Folder 94)
  - Cost Commission (Box 11, Folder 95)
  - Financial Overview (Box 11, Folder 96 - 97)
  - Finances, Circa 1979 (Box 11, Folder 98)
  - Docket
    - 77-111 (Box 11, Folder 99)
    - #80-021 (Box 11, Folder 100)
  - Cost Commission
    - Court Case (Box 12, Folder 101)
    - 1977 Sep (Box 12, Folder 102)
    - Rates (Box 12, Folder 103)
    - Application (Box 12, Folder 104)
  - Rate Increase
    - 1976 May 1 (Box 12, Folder 105)
    - Application (Box 12, Folder 106)
    - Application Receipted Copy (Box 12, Folder 107)
  - Connecticut Commission on Hospitals and Health Care (Box 12, Folder 108)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 12, Folder 109)
    - Questions (Box 13, Folder 110)
    - Financial Data (Box 13, Folder 111 - 112)
    - Financial Reports (Box 13, Folder 113 - 114)
    - Staff Reports, Budget (Box 13, Folder 115)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 14, Folder 116 - 118)
    - Application, 1983-1984 (Box 14, Folder 119)
    - 1984 (Box 14, Folder 120 - 121)
    - Institute of Living (Box 14, Folder 122)
  - Auditors and Audit
    - Report (Box 14, Folder 123)
    - Financial Statements (Box 15, Folder 124 - 125)
    - Financial Statements, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 126)
    - Financial Statements, 1977-1978 (Box 15, Folder 127)
    - Financial Statements, 1981-1982 (Box 15, Folder 128)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 15, Folder 129 - 130)
  - Cedarhurst School Budget (Box 15, Folder 131)
  - Income and Expense, 1981-1982 (Box 15, Folder 132)
  - Coopers and Lybrand (Box 15, Folder 133)
  - Financial Overview, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 134 - 137)
  - Annual Reports (Box 16, Folder 138)
  - Miscellaneous Finances, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 139 - 141)
  - Miscellaneous Finance, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 142)
  - Cash Collections (Box 18, Folder 143)
  - Budget
    - 1978-1979 (Box 18, Folder 144)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 18, Folder 145 - 146)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 18, Folder 147 - 148)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 18, Folder 149 - 150)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 18, Folder 151)
- Dedication records, 1989-1990; Accession 1990-A-159
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2025
  - Toursand Publicity, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 2)
  - Dinner: Graduate Club, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Hold Date" Letters, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Guest List, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6 - 7)
  - Speeches, Plaques, Certificates, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Mementos, Invitations, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Catering, Lighting, Florist, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)